# WILLIAM MAYOR

#### FULL-STACK WEB ENGINEER, SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

www.williammayor.co.uk jobs@williammayor.co.uk +447500222670

**Technical** 

Python

HTML / CSS / Javascript

Git

PostgreSQL / MySQL OS X / Linux Knockout.js / Underscore.js / SASS Heroku / AWS TDD / Selenium

Docker / Vagrant

**Profile** 

I'm a code monkey at heart; I love building solutions. I am a usability enthusiast, lots of my work at Diversity and Ability focusses around making software and the web accessible and usable. I also enjoy exploring and playing with data, my MRes research involved simulating million-node networks. I think coding is fun and rewarding and that more people should do it. I work with an educational trust to deliver programming courses to 16-18 year-olds. In my spare time I like to code, I also enjoy wood turning, cooking, and the occasional video game.

### Experience

**BAFTA** 2014 to present Software Engineer

I help build and grow BAFTA's commercial offerings. This includes digital media distribution platforms, awards services, and

copyright tools.

**The Media Institute** 2014 to 2015 Software Engineer I worked on several Innovate UK projects looking to expand the cutting edge of digital tools in the media industry. I also helped to build, run, and analyse several large-scale Amazon Mechanical Turk user studies.

**Diversity and Ability** 2009 to present Associate Director, Head of IT I setup, run, and maintain the internal IT provision for Diversity and Ability. I also work as their sole web developer; managing their entire web ecosystem.

**Freelance** 2009 to present Software Engineer, Web Developer I have built many websites and software projects. Details of the open source ones can be found on my <u>GitHub page</u>.

MRes Dissertation 2012 Researcher I worked on improving the reliability of the BitTorrent protocol by fully decentralising the peer discovery mechanisms. Paper published in IEEE P2P2013.

**BSc Dissertation** 2011 Software Engineer

I built a collaborative, real-time, cloud-based IDE using Google Wave technology.

#### Education

MRes Crime and Security Science 2011 to 2012

University College London, UK

**BSc Computer Science** 2008 to 2011 University College London, UK

## References

Ingemar Cox Director of Research

Computer Science Department, University College London

**Atif Choudhury** CEO Diversity and Ability

For privacy reasons, contact details are available on request. Public profiles are available: Ingemar, Atif